A Guide to the Fairfax Hall (Waynesboro, Va.) records, 1918-1965
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
Fairfax Hall (Waynesboro, Va.) records, 1918-1965
The Library of Virginia
42529
2.4 cu. ft. and 9 boxes and 2 volumes
Fairfax Hall (Waynesboro, Va.)
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Gift of Diane Jones Langston of Moseley, Virginia.
Historical Information
John Noble Maxwell (1888-1932) opened Fairfax Hall as a girls' school in Waynesboro, Virginia, in 1920. On his death in 1932, his widow, Octavia Goode Maxwell (1892-1974) ran the school until 1936. That year, Fairfax Hall was sold to W. B. Gates. It operated as a school until closed in 1975.
Scope and Content
Papers, 1918-1965, of Fairfax Hall, a girls' school located in Waynesboro, Virginia, containing account books, accounts, administrator and executor papers, catalogs, certificates, correspondence, financial records, invoices, ledgers, registers, scrapbooks, stock certificates, tax records, yearbooks, and other papers detailing the history and operations of Fairfax Hall from 1920 to 1936; as well as concerning the private life and professional career of Octavia Goode Maxwell (1892-1974).
Arrangement
This collection is arranged into the following series:
Series I: Fairfax Hall records, 1920-1936
Series II: Octavia Goode Maxwell papers, 1918-1965
Contents List
- Series I: Fairfax Hall records, 1920-1936., Extent: 5 boxes and 2 volumes. (Box 1-5)
  Fairfax Hall records, 1920-1936, contain account books, catalogs, correspondence, financial records, ledgers, registers, stock certificates, yearbooks, and other papers detailing the history and operations of Fairfax Hall, a girls' school operated by John Noble Maxwell (1888-1932) and Octavia Goode Maxwell (1892-1974). Yearbooks, 1921-1936, highlight the school and student life and activities; catalogs, 1920-1932, detail the operations of the school and classes offered; correspondence, 1928, 1932-1936, mainly concerns the school's difficulties during the Great Depression; and financial records, stock certificates, registers, account books, and ledgers, 1926-1936, concern the financial operations of the school.
  - Fair Facts, 1921 (Box 1)
  - Fair Facts, 1923 (Box 1)
  - Fair Facts, 1924 (Box 1)
  - Fair Facts, 1925 (Box 2)
  - Fair Facts, 1926 (Box 2)
  - Fair Facts, 1927 (Box 2)
  - Fair Facts, 1928 (Box 3)
  - Fair Facts, 1929 (Box 3)
  - Fair Facts, 1932 (Box 3)
  - Fair Facts, 1933 (Box 4)
  - Fair Facts, 1934 (Box 4)
  - Fair Facts, 1935 (Box 4)
  - Fair Facts, 1936 (Box 4)
  - Fairfax Hall catalog, 1920-1921 (Box 5)
  - Fairfax Hall catalog, 1926-1927 (Box 5)
  - Fairfax Hall catalog, 1927-1928 (Box 5)
  - Fairfax Hall catalog, 1928-1929 (Box 5)
  - Fairfax Hall catalog, 1929-1930 (Box 5)
  - Fairfax Hall catalog, 1931-1932 (Box 5)
  - Correspondence with faculty and staff (Margaret Bransford, Hattie E. Brown, Thomas L. Chrisman, Fannie Sue Coleman, Alice Forsell, Myra Matthews, Ebba Noer, Amy Plummer, Mary E. Thomas, Carrie Bell Vaughan), 1928, 1932-1936 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Financial papers, 1926-1934 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Stock certificate book (Box 6)
  - Account book, 1926-1936 (Box 6)
  - Acount ledger (trial balance, account journal, check register, cash disbursements), 1931-1936
  - Transfer journal and check register, 1924, 1929-1932